ABOUT ME

I'm an Android Developer skilled in Java, Kotlin, Retrofit, Jetpack and all other flashy new (and old) things. I love programming and I'm glad i was fortunate enough to combine my hobby and job into one.

Apart from programming I love spending time with my fiancee and our 5 cats, making model WW2 airplanes, listening to audio books and going out into nature away from civilization.

	8 years
ANDROID	
KOTLIN	4 years
JAVA	10 years
DI (KOIN, Dagger 2, KODEIN, Hilt)	6 years
COROUTINES	3 years
SQL	9 years
NoSQL	6 years
GIT	9 years
.NET	5 years
PYTHON	1 year
RxJava	3 years
ARCore, OpenGL,	1 year
Sceneform	1 year
COMPOSE	5 years
Linux C++	1 year

LINKS

GitHub

https://github.com/azentner1

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrejzentner/

Andrej Zentner

SENIOR ANDROID DEVELOPER

+ 385 91 1221 116

andrej.zentner@mscommunity.net

WORK EXPERIENCE

PENN INTERACTIVE (USA)

I LIVI IIVILIVACIIVL (03/

Apr 2021 - May 2023

CODA (USA)

Dec 2019 – Apr 2021

STRING (UK)

Mar 2019 - Dec 2019

GLOBAL.ID (USA)

May 2018 - Mar 2019

TELTECH (USA)

May 2016 – May 2018

IMPADDO (EU)

Jan 2015 - May 2016

SIEMENS

Apr 2014 - Jan 2015

STARNET

May 2013 - Apr 2014

MICROSOFT

Jul 2011 – Jun 2012

Senior Android Developer – Remote

- Developed and maintained a sportsbook app
- Team member
- Kotlin, Coroutines, RoomDB, MVVM, Compose, KMM

Senior Android Developer/Team Lead-Remote

- Developed and maintained a Music Video Streaming app
- Team Lead
- Kotlin, Coroutines, LiveData, MVVM, Realm, OTT

Senior Android Developer – Remote

- Developed an AR app using Sceneform and OpenGL
- Team member
- Kotlin, ARCore, Sceneform, OpenGL, RoomDB, MVVM

Senior Android Developer - Remote

- Worked on payment system integration
- Team membe
- Scrum, Agile
- Kotlin, Dagger 2, RxJava, Retrofit, RoomDB

Senior Android Developer - Remote

- Developed and maintained a call blocking application - RoboKiller
- Team member
- Scrum, Agile
- Kotlin, Android Jetpack, Coroutines, LiveData, Retrofit, Mockito, OTT

Android Team Lead - Remote

- Developed and maintained several B2B and Play Store applications
- Lead a team of 4 developers
- Scrum Agile
- Java, SQLite, Dagger 2, RxJava, Mockito, OTT, video streaming

Senior Java Developer

- Designed, implemented and maintained features for a robust monitoring and charging system, in use by large telecoms (T-Mobile, Verizon, etc..)
- Scrum
- Java, SQL, Python

.NET Developer

- Designed, implemented and maintained features across multiple desktop and web applications
- NET (C# and VB), MSSQL, JavaScript, DevExpress

.NET Intern

- Worked on internal applications
 - .NET, MSSQL, Windows Phone SDK, JavaScript

Note:

I'm only open for fully remote positions.

You can find my code samples on GitHub. Newest repo is always the closest to the way I'm writting code at the moment.

Education

FACULTY OF ORGANISATION AND INFORMATICS

2009. – 2014.

Bachelor of Computer Science Information Technology

CIVIL ENGINEERING

2001. – 2005.

High School Diploma

NOTABLE PROJECTS

RoboKiller

Android Call Blocking application. 500k monthly, 40k daily active users. Implementing new features, bug fixing and maintenance. Technologies used: Kotlin, Retrofit, Jetpack, MVVM

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.robokiller.app

Global ID

Android application that aims to unify various identity verification methods into one. 100k+ users. Technologies used: Kotlin, Retrofit, Jetpack, RxJava, Dagger 2, MVP

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=net.globalid

Triller

Social streaming app. Tik-tok alternative. 10 million+ users. Technologies used: Java, Kotlin, RoomDB, OpenGL

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=co.triller.droid

Coda Collection

An app for streaming video content related to Music. Tehnologies used: Kotlin, Coroutines, LiveData, MVVM,

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=co.codacollection.coda

Barstool Sportsbook

Application for Sports Betting. 100k+ users. Technologies used: Kotlin, Compose, MVVM, KMM https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.png.sportsbook.googl

PUBLICATIONS

Apr 2018

Multithreading in .NET and Java: A Reality Check

http://www.jcomputers.us/index.php?m=content&c=i ndex&a=show&catid=196&id=2793